Henry Justin Allen Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Henry Justin Allen Papers 1896-1942 (bulk 1919-1942)
MSS50781
Allen, Henry Justin, 1868-1950
80,000 items 214 containers 85.4 linear feet
Manuscript Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Publisher and governor of and United States senator from Kansas. Correspondence, supplemented by speeches, articles, printed matter, clippings, and miscellaneous papers relating to Allen's public career, especially his terms as governor and senator.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Allen family.; Allen, Henry Justin, 1868-1950.; Gompers, Samuel, 1850-1924.; Hays, Will H. (Will Harrison), 1879-1954--Correspondence.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952--Correspondence.; Landon, Alfred M. (Alfred Mossman), 1887-1987--Correspondence.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951--Correspondence.; White, William Allen, 1868-1944--Correspondence.; Wood, Leonard, 1860-1927--Correspondence.
Organizations
Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Tidewater Association.; Industrial Workers of the World.; Kansas. Court of Industrial Relations.; Ku Klux Klan (1915- ); National Nonpartisan League.; Near East Relief (Organization); Republican National Convention.; Republican Party (U.S.: 1854- ); Save the Children (U.S.)
Subjects
Child welfare--Societies, etc.; Labor unions.
Places
Kansas--Politics and government--1865-1950.; United States--Politics and government--1901-1953.
Occupations
Governors--Kansas.; Publishers.; Senators, U.S. Congress--Kansas.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The papers of Henry Justin Allen, publisher, governor of Kansas, and United States senator, were given to the Library of Congress in 1966-1967 by his daughter, Henrietta Allen Holmes.
Access and Restrictions
The Allen Papers are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1868, Sept. 11 Born, Pittsfield, Pa.
1890 Graduated, Baker University, Baldwin, Kans.
1893 Married Elsie J. Nuzman
1894 Became editor of Manhattan Nationalist, Manhattan, Kans.
1907-1928 Owner of Wichita Beacon; continued as chairman of the board of Beacon Publishing Co. until his death
1912 Delegate, Republican National Convention Delegate, Progressive National Convention
1914 Unsuccessful candidate for governor of Kansas on Progressive ticket
1916 Delegate, Progressive National Convention
1917-1918 Served with American Red Cross in France
1918 Headed YMCA activities in 35th Division in France during World War I
1919-1923 Governor of Kansas
1923-1924 Special commissioner with Near East Relief
1928 Director of publicity, Republican National Committee
1929-1930 United States senator from Kansas
1932 Assistant to Charles Dawes in Reconstruction Finance Corp. Director of publicity, Republican National Committee
1935 Became editor of Topeka State Journal
1950, Jan. 17 Died, Wichita, Kans.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Henry Justin Allen (1868-1950) span the years 1896-1942, with the bulk concentrated in the period 1919-1942. The collection is organized in three series: Pre-Gubernatorial File, Gubernatorial File, and Post-Gubernatorial File. Letters concerning family affairs, including occasional letters to his wife, are scattered throughout the collection. Material relating to his business activities is located in both the Gubernatorial and Post-Gubernatorial Files.
Allen served four years as governor of Kansas, 1919-1923, and the achievements and controversies that marked these years are documented in the Gubernatorial File. Arranged in seventeen subseries, this series is composed primarily of correspondence and touches upon virtually all aspects of Allen's tenure as governor. The material concerning the Kansas Court of Industrial Relations and a subseries on labor relations is particularly complete, while the relatively small Presidential File is a good source of information for Republican Party politics in the months preceding the National Republican Convention in 1920. Other topics include the Ku Klux Klan, the Industrial Workers of the World, the National Nonpartisan League and Allen's debate over labor relations with Samuel Gompers. The extensive General Correspondence subseries relates to all aspects of Allen's tenure, and letters sent and received from prominent persons form the basis of the Special Correspondence. Prominent correspondents in the latter group include Will H. Hays, Harold L. Ickes, Alfred M. Landon, Arthur H. Vandenberg, William Allen White, and Leonard Wood.
The Post-Gubernatorial File chronicles Allen's public career after leaving the governorship, including his brief tenure as United States senator, 1929-1930, and is divided into thirteen subseries. The material in the Special Correspondence and General Correspondence subseries relates to all aspects of his career during this period, as does the material in the Publications and Speech Material files. The less-publicized facets of Allen's career, including his activities on behalf of Near East Relief, the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Tidewater Association, and Save the Children (U.S.), are also amply documented.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in three series:
Pre-Gubernatorial File, 1896-1918
Gubernatorial File, 1918-1923
Post-Gubernatorial File, circa 1923-1942
http://lccn.loc.gov/mm73050781
Container List
- Pre-Gubernatorial File, 1896-1918 (Box A1-A2)
  - General Correspondence, 1896-1918 (Box A1)
    Letters received and copies of letter sent with attached and related material.
    Arranged chronologically by year.
  - Speeches and Articles, 1897-1918 (Box A1-A2)
    Holograph, typed, and printed copies of speeches and articles.
    - 1897-1903 (Box A1)
    - 1904-1918, undated (Box A2)
- Gubernatorial File, 1918-1923 (Box B1-B75)
  - Special Correspondence, 1918-1923 (Box B1)
    Letters received and copies of letters sent with attached and related matter.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent and therein chronologically.
    - Beveridge, Albert (Box B1)
    - Coolidge, Calvin
    - Harding, Warren G.
    - Hays, Will H.
    - Hoover, Herbert
    - Ickes, Harold L.
    - Johnson, Hiram
    - Landon, Alfred
    - McCormick, Medill
    - Pinchot, Gifford
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - Taft, William H.
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
    - White, William Allen
    - Wood, Leonard
  - General Correspondence, 1919-1923 (Box B2-B27)
    - 1919 (Box B2)
    - (12 folders), (13 folders); (11 folders) (Box B3, Box B4, Box B5, Box B6)
    - 1920, (12 folders); (11 folders); (10 folders) (Box B7, Box B8, Box B9, Box B10, Box B11, Box B12, Box B13)
    - 1921, (10 folders); (11 folders); (12 folders); (13 folders) (Box B14, Box B15, Box B16, Box B17, Box B18, Box B19, Box B20, Box B21)
    - 1922, (13 folders); (12 folders); (11 folders) (Box B22, Box B23, Box B24, Box B25, Box B26, Box B27)
    - 1923
  - Kansas Court of Industrial Relations, 1919-1923 (Box B28-B37)
    Correspondence, speeches, articles, reports, bills, clippings, and printed matter.
    Arranged by type of material and therein chronologically by year.
    - Correspondence (Box B28)
      - 1919, (9 folders)
      - 1920, (12 folders); (10 folders); (11 folders) (Box B29, Box B30, Box B31)
      - 1921, (10 folders); (12 folders) (Box B32, Box B33)
      - 1922 (Box B34)
      - (10 folders), (12 folders) (Box B35)
      - 1923, (13 folders)
    - Speeches, articles, reports, and bills, (2 folders) (Box B36)
    - Clippings, (3 folders)
    - Printed matter, (4 folders); (11 folders) (Box B37)
  - Labor Relations, 1919-1922 (Box B38-B44)
    Correspondence, clippings, and printed matter.
    - Correspondence (Box B38)
      - 1919, (11 folders); (13 folders) (Box B39)
      - 1920, (5 folders) (Box B40)
      - 1921, (8 folders)
      - 1922 (Box B41)
      - (12 folders), (7 folders) (Box B42)
    - Clippings
    - Printed matter, (3 folders); (8 folders) (Box B43, Box B44)
  - Allen-Samuel Gompers Debate, 1920-1921 (Box B45-B46)
    Correspondence, printed matter, and reference material.
    - Correspondence, 1920-1921, (9 folders) (Box B45)
    - Clippings, (3 folders)
    - Debate copies (Box B46)
    - Printed matter, (6 folders)
    - Reference material, (3 folders)
  - International Workers of the World and National Nonpartisan League, 1919-1922 (Box B47)
    Correspondence and printed matter.
    - Correspondence, 1919-1922, (9 folders) (Box B47)
    - Printed matter
  - Ku Klux Klan, 1922-1923 (Box B48-B49)
    - Correspondence (Box B48)
      - 1922, (12 folders); (3 folders) (Box B49)
      - 1923
    - Clippings, (6 folders)
    - Printed matter
  - Presidential File, 1920 (Box B50)
    Correspondence, speeches, and printed matter.
    Arranged by type of material.
    - Correspondence, 1920, (9 folders) (Box B50)
    - Speeches, printed matter
  - Constitutional Amendments, 1919-1923 (Box B51-B52)
    - Correspondence, 1919-1923, (11 folders) (Box B51)
    - Clippings, (2 folders) (Box B52)
    - Printed matter, (7 folders)
  - Legislative File, 1920-1921, (13 folders) (Box B53)
    Correspondence.
  - Thirty-fifth Division Controversy, 1918-1919 (Box B54-B55)
    - Correspondence (Box B54)
      - 1918
      - 1919, (10 folders); (5 folders) (Box B55)
    - Clippings, (5 folders)
    - Printed matter
  - Receptions for Returning Kansas Troops, 1919, (9 folders); (11 folders) (Box B56-B57, Box B56, Box B57)
  - Congratulations on Reelection, 1919-1920, (11 folders) (Box B57)
    Congratulatory correspondence.
  - Applications, 1919-1921 (Box B58-B59)
    Applications for position.
    Arranged by office and therein chronologically by year.
    - State accountant, 1919-1920 (Box B58)
    - Judge, District Court, Jan. 1920
    - Board of Review, 1920-1921, (4 folders)
    - State bank commissioner, 1920-1921, (3 folders)
    - Sheriff, Pawnee County, 1921, (5 folders) (Box B59)
    - State printer, 1921, (6 folders)
  - Speeches and Articles, 1919-1923, (13 folders) (Box B60)
    Speeches and articles.
    Arranged chronologically by month.
  - Invitations, 1919-1923 (Box B61-B72)
    Invitations.
    - Jan.-May 1919, (11 folders) (Box B61)
    - June-Aug. 1919, (12 folders) (Box B62)
    - Sept.-Nov. 1919, (12 folders) (Box B63)
    - Dec. 1919-Mar. 1920, (11 folders) (Box B64)
    - Apr.-May 1920, (12 folders) (Box B65)
    - June-Nov. 1920, (15 folders) (Box B66)
    - Dec. 1920-Mar. 1921, (12 folders) (Box B67)
    - Apr.-July 1921, (13 folders) (Box B68)
    - Aug.-Nov. 1921, (14 folders) (Box B69)
    - Dec. 1921- Mar. 1922, (14 folders) (Box B70)
    - Apr.-Aug. 1922, (11 folders) (Box B71)
    - Sept. 1922-Jan. 1923, (14 folders) (Box B72)
  - Miscellany (Box B73-B75)
    Reports, clippings, bills and receipts, printed matter, and other items.
    - Reports, clippings, and bills, (6 folders) (Box B73)
    - Receipts, statements, (5 folders)
    - Printed matter, (6 folders); (3 folders) (Box B74, Box B75)
    - Miscellaneous items, (5 folders)
- Post-Gubernatorial File, circa 1923-1942 (Box C1-C137)
  - Special Correspondence (Box C1-C12)
    Letters received and copies of letters sent with attached and related material.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
    - Akerson, George (Box C1)
    - Alden, C. E.
    - Allen, Henry J., (2 folders)
    - American Legion
    - American Legion, Kansas Department
    - Amrine, M. F.
    - Archer, Laird W., (5 folders)
    - Ayres, W. A., (2 folders)
    - Bailey, Roy F., (3 folders)
    - Baker, Benson
    - Black, Richard E.
    - Bowers, L. B.
    - Bragg, Thomas, (3 folders)
    - Bristow, Joseph L. (Box C2)
    - Brown, Edwin
    - Butcher, Thomas W.
    - Butler, A. T.
    - Caldwell, Robert J.
    - Capper, Arthur, (6 folders)
    - Carruth, Arthur J., (3 folders)
    - Carter, Mrs. Jonathan B.
    - Castle, William R., Jr.
    - Chadbourne, William M.
    - Chandler, C. J., (4 folders)
    - Chandler, C., (6 folders)
    - Clark, George A. (Box C3)
    - Claus, Charlie
    - Cowie, Dan
    - Crane, A. E.
    - Davidson, J. E.
    - Davies, Gomer T.
    - Denton, Albert H., (2 folders)
    - Downie, Ernest R.
    - Edmonds, Leslie, (2 folders)
    - Endres, Benjamin F., (2 folders)
    - Evans, Earle W., (4 folders)
    - Fields, John
    - Fisher, Jesse Clyde
    - Foulston, Robert F.
    - Gannett, Frank E., (3 folders)
    - Goddard, Wendell
    - Goodrich, James P.
    - Gray, Malcomb
    - Green, Hugh (Box C4)
    - Griffith, Bruce, (2 folders)
    - Goyer, U. S., (4 folders)
    - Hamilton, Clad
    - Hamilton, John D. M., (2 folders)
    - Hamilton, Peter
    - Harvey, Alice, (3 folders)
    - Haskell, Harry J.
    - Hegler, Ben F., (2 folders)
    - Hegler, Burns
    - High, Stanley
    - Hinkel, Allen W.
    - Hinshaw, David
    - Hoch, Homer
    - Hoover, Herbert, (3 folders)
    - Hope, Clifford R., (2 folders)
    - Hopkins, E. N.
    - Hopkins, Richard J.
    - Isely, C. C., (2 folders) (Box C5)
    - Jardine, William M.
    - Jarrell, Arch W., (2 folders)
    - Jones, Richard Lloyd, (3 folders)
    - Judd, Clarence, (5 folders)
    - Kiplinger, W. M.
    - Kirkwood, John
    - Knox, Frank
    - Kreiselman, Lilien, (2 folders) (Box C6)
    - Lambertson, W. P., (2 folders)
    - Landon, Alfred M., (6 folders)
    - Lee, Frederic
    - Levand, Louis (Box C7)
    - Levand, Max, (3 folders)
    - Long, Chester I., (2 folders)
    - Long, Sylvester A.
    - McDermott, George T.
    - McGugin, Harold A., (2 folders)
    - McIntosh, A. J.
    - McIvor, Donald H., (2 folders)
    - MacVeagh, Charlton, (2 folders)
    - MacVicar, John G.
    - Mercer, J. H., (2 folders)
    - Miller, A. L., (2 folders)
    - Miller, A. Q., (2 folders)
    - Mitchell, Charles L., (3 folders)
    - Motter, Harvey H., (4 folders) (Box C8)
    - Mulvane, David W., (2 folders)
    - Noyes, Frank B.
    - Peterson, Elmer T., (6 folders)
    - Pettijohn, L. J. (Box C9)
    - Phelps, Charles H.
    - Ratner, Payne
    - Reed, Clyde, (9 folders)
    - Richart, Willard, (2 folders) (Box C10)
    - Roberts, Roy, (4 folders)
    - Scandrett, Richard B.
    - Scott, Charles F., (6 folders)
    - Shinn, E. W.
    - Simpson, Anita
    - Simpson, Lacey M.
    - Smith, Fred Dumont
    - Smith, Lucille
    - Sparks, Charles I.
    - Spender, J. Alfred
    - Sponable, Frank W., (2 folders) (Box C11)
    - Stauffer, Oscar, (5 folders)
    - Strong, James G., (3 folders)
    - Thorpe, Merle
    - Trigg, Fred C., (3 folders)
    - United Spanish War Veterans
    - Van Auken, H. M.
    - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
    - Vickrey, Charles V.
    - Wagner, Charles L.
    - Waldo, Richard H., (2 folders)
    - Walter, Stephen M., (3 folders)
    - Weeks, Bryan T.
    - West, Will G.
    - White, William Allen, (9 1⁄2 folders) (Box C12)
    - White, William L., (1 1⁄2 folders)
    - Wichita Chamber of Commerce, Wichita, Kans.
    - Willette, Ray T.
    - Williams, Whiting
    - Winrod, Gerald B.
    - Woodring, Harry H.
  - General Correspondence, 1926-1942 (Box C13-C51)
    - 1926 (Box C13)
      - A-D
      - E-L (Box C14)
      - M-R (Box C15)
      - S-Z (Box C16)
    - 1927 (Box C17)
      - A-C
      - D-H (Box C18)
      - I-P (Box C19)
      - P-S (Box C20)
      - T-Z (Box C21)
    - 1928 (Box C22)
      - A-E
      - F-L (Box C23)
      - M-Q (Box C24)
      - R-T (Box C25)
      - U-Z (Box C26)
    - 1929 (Box C27)
      - A-Z
      - Miscellaneous, (8 folders); (10 folders) (Box C28, Box C29)
    - 1930, (8 folders); (10 folders); (12 folders); (2 folders) (Box C30, Box C31, Box C32, Box C33, Box C34)
    - 1931, (8 folders)
    - 1932, (10 folders) (Box C35, Box C36)
    - 1933, (5 folders) (Box C37)
    - 1934, (6 folders)
    - 1935, (10 folders) (Box C38)
    - 1936, (10 folders); (14 folders) (Box C39, Box C40, Box C41, Box C42)
    - 1937, (9 folders); (10 folders) (Box C43, Box C44, Box C45)
    - 1938 (Box C46)
    - (12 folders), (11 folders) (Box C47)
    - 1939 (Box C48)
    - (11 folders), (10 folders) (Box C49)
    - 1940, (10 folders); (4 folders) (Box C50, Box C51)
    - 1941, ( folders)
    - 1942
  - United States Government (Box C52-C66)
    Correspondence, reports, bills, applications for position and appointments, clippings, printed matter, financial matter, and miscellaneous material.
    Arranged alphabetically by name of government department, agency, or bureau and therein by type of material.
    - Agricultural Credit Corporation (Box C52)
    - Agricultural, Department of
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
      - Cheyenne bottoms
      - Drought relief
      - Grain grading
      - Loans to farmers
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Regulatory work
      - Secretary of agriculture
    - Board of Tax Appeals (Box C53)
    - Civil Service Commission
    - Commerce, Department of
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
      - Census, Kansas
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - National Commission on Unemployment
      - Secretary of commerce
    - Customs Bureau
    - Federal Farm Board
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
      - Appointments, members, Frizzell and Umberger
      - Attack of Chamber of Commerce
      - Chairman, Stone, J.C.
      - Complaints against board
      - Favorable comment
      - Grain corporations
      - Grain marketing suggestions (Box C54)
      - Grain storage
      - Kansas cooperative situation
      - Kansas wheat pool
      - Livestock
      - Loans
      - Loans to farmers, procedure
      - Marketing contracts
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Publicity suggestions
      - Reed, Clyde-Alexander M. Legge debate
      - Releases
      - Unfavorable comment (Box C55)
      - Wheat situation, 1931-1932, (2 folders)
    - Federal Farm Loan Board, (2 folders)
    - Federal Land Bank, (2 folders)
    - Federal Power Commission
    - Federal Radio Commission, (2 folders)
    - Federal Reserve Board
      - Appointments
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
    - Federal Reserve Board, Wichita Branch Bank (Box C56)
    - Federal Trade Commission
    - Government Printing Office, (2 folders)
    - Home Loan Bank
    - Interior, Department of
      - Appointments
      - Boulder Dam projects
    - Interior, Department of
      - Indian affairs
      - Miscellaneous (Box C57)
        - General, (2 folders)
        - Illiteracy Committee
      - National park matters
      - Tax on doctors
    - Interstate Commerce Commission, (2 folders)
    - Justice, Department of
      - Appointments
        - General, (3 folders)
        - Supreme Court (Box C58)
        - United States Marshall
      - Lindbergh, Charles, case
      - Miscellaneous
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box C59)
      - Prohibition, (2 folders)
    - Labor, Department of
      - Appointments
        - General, (2 folders)
        - Secretary of labor
      - Miscellaneous
    - Navy, Department of (Box C60)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Releases from Navy
      - Shearer investigation
      - United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Md.
        - Appointments
        - Introductions
    - Post Office, Department of (Box C61)
      - Airmail routes
      - Appointments
        - General
        - Postmasters, (2 folders)
      - Buildings, (2 folders)
      - Clerical assistance (Box C62)
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Promotion, (2 folders)
      - Reinstatement, (2 folders)
      - Rural routes, (2 folders)
      - Transfers
      - Wichita Post Office
    - Reconstruction Finance Corporation (Box C63)
      - Allen, Henry J.
      - Allen, Henry J., releases and statements
      - Appointments
        - Advisory Board
        - Secretarial
      - Branch banking
      - Congratulatory letters
      - Miscellaneous
    - State, Department
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
      - Foreign service, favorable comment
      - Miscellaneous, (2 folders)
      - Secretary of state
    - Tariff Commission, (2 folders)
    - Treasury, Department of
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
        - Public Health Service
        - Receiver
      - Customs, duty on tractors
      - Federal Reserve Bank
      - Internal Revenue
      - Kansas City Joint Stock Land Bank, (2 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders) (Box C64)
      - Port of entry
      - Russian lumber importation
      - Russian manganese
    - United States Employees Compensation Commission
    - United States Shipping Board, (2 folders)
    - Veterans Administration
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
      - Compensation, (2 folders)
      - Compensation, Spanish-American War back pay (Box C65)
      - Hospital
        - Kansas
        - Wichita, Kans.
      - Hospitalization
      - Hospitals
      - Loans
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Special acts
    - War, Department of (Box C66)
      - Appointments, (2 folders)
        - Flying cadets
        - Philippine Islands, (2 folders)
        - West Point, N.Y., United States Naval Academy, (2 folders)
      - Fort Riley Air Corps removal
      - Miscellaneous, (3 folders)
      - Near East Relief Warehouse
      - Philippine Islands
      - Reserve Officer' Training Corps Medical Unit
      - Secretary of war, Hurley, Patrick J.
      - Veterans Hospital, Kansas
  - Campaign File, 1930-1936 (Box C67-C78)
    Correspondence, reports, invitations, petitions, photographs, press releases, clippings, notes, public relations material, and miscellaneous items.
    Organized into three groups: Senate, 1930; National Campaign, 1932; and National Campaign, 1936, and therein alphabetically by subject, topic, jurisdiction, or type of material.
    - Senate, 1930 (Box C67)
      - Advertising
      - Analysis of primary vote
      - Brinkley, John R.
      - Campaign issues
      - Chairman (by county)
        - Allen
        - Anderson
        - Atchison
        - Barber
        - Barton
        - Bourbon
        - Brown
        - Butler
        - Chase
        - Chautauqua
        - Cherokee
        - Cheyenne
        - Clark
        - Clay
        - Cloud
        - Coffey
        - Comanche
        - Cowley
        - Crawford
        - Decator
        - Dickinson (Box C68)
        - Doniphan
        - Douglas
        - Edwards
        - Elk
        - Ellis
        - Ellsworth
        - Finney
        - Ford
        - Franklin
        - Geary
        - Gove
        - Graham
        - Grant
        - Gray
        - Greeley
        - Greenwood
        - Hamilton
        - Harper
        - Harvey
        - Haskell
        - Hodgeman
        - Jackson
        - Jefferson
        - Jewell
        - Johnson
        - Kearny
        - Kingman
        - Kiowa
        - Labette
        - Lane
        - Leavenworth (Box C69)
        - Lincoln
        - Linn
        - Logan
        - Lyon
        - Marion
        - Marshall
        - McPherson
        - Meade
        - Miami
        - Mitchell
        - Montgomery
        - Morris
        - Morton
        - Nemaha
        - Neosho
        - Ness
        - Norton
        - Osage
        - Osborne (Box C70)
        - Ottawa
        - Pawnee
        - Phillips
        - Pottawatomie
        - Pratt
        - Rawlins
        - Reno
        - Republic
        - Rice
        - Riley
        - Rooks
        - Rush
        - Russell
        - Saline
        - Scott
        - Sedgwick
        - Seward
        - Sheridan
        - Sherman
        - Smith
        - Stafford
        - Stanton
        - Stevens
        - Sumner
        - Thomas
        - Trego
        - Wabaunsee
        - Wallace
        - Washington
        - Wichita
        - Wilson
        - Woodson
        - Wyandotte